WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Wait one moment.
She can decide whether or not she
wants to throw these away.
Quite right.
But how would it be funded?
There's quite a lot in the kitty
and we'd have another campaign.
There'll be plenty of volunteers to
keep up standards.
For how long? And what about the
cricket?
We'd have to re-site the pitch, My
Lord. Of course it would take work
~ but we've got until the summer.
~ Think what we're gaining.
A beautiful garden of remembrance.
Where people can walk and sit
and think about their loved ones.
They can come here from all around
and spend an hour with their sacred
memories in peace and at rest.
This pitch has been prepared over
years
with a great deal of work for the
cricket.
That field below Peckham wood could
be made into a pitch.
Surely the right place is in the
village where people pass every day.
Will it be peaceful and quiet?
A fit place for mourning?
It's what they're doing in Sowerby
and I'm certain it's where most of
them will be.
And is our memorial to be no better
than most of them?
It comes down to priorities,
Lord Grantham.
Which is more important, a game of
cricket or the loss of a son in the
course of his duty?
Well, this is it, then.
There's something I wanna say.
I'm sorry I put you through all that
trouble.
Forget it.
~ It's in t'past. ~ Well, you've been a
good friend to me, Thomas.
If anyone had told me that I'd have
been friends with a...
man like you I'd have not believed
them.
But we have been friends.
And I'm sad to see the back of you.
I am.
We can always write.
I'm not much at letter writing.
I'll do me best.
But in case we don't meet again...
I hope you find some happiness.
I do, truly.
I hope the same for you too, Jimmy.
I'll be dandy.
I'd best be off.
~ I'm sorry Jimmy's gone.
~ I know.
It were nice having a bonny face
about the house.
We'll have to make do with Mr
Molesley.
How are you studies going?
~ Slowly. ~ It's bound to be hard when
you've not been at school for a
while.
It's not hard, it's impossible.
But what's the answer?
Is the pudding ready to go up?
~ Mrs Patmore? The pudding.
~ Sorry. I was miles away.
There's a sauce to go with that.
On one tray or will Mr Barrow help?
One tray, please. I can't be
bothered to fight with him.
Jimmy, where are you when we need
you?
~ Ooh, Mr Carson.
~ What is it now?
Now that Jimmy, erm, James, has
gone,
do I take it that I am now
first footman?
Since you are the only footman, you
are first, second, third and last.
Make what you will of it.
Mr Moseley, we are nearly at the end
of those distinctions.
There will come a time when a
household is lucky to boast any
footman.
Now get that up to the dining room.
Did it not go well this morning?
I was disappointed, if you must
know.
But it's early days.
George is coming on so fast.
It's wonderful how they seem to
change week by week at his age.
He's rather sweet, isn't he?
How are you getting on with repairing
the fire damage?
Oh, they're all being marvellous
but I do feel such an idiot.
Maybe because you behaved like an
idiot.
The good thing is it'll be sorted
out in a day or two.
~ I got this letter from Charles
Blake? ~ What does he want?
An art historian he knows is writing
a book on della Francesca.
He wasn't aware we had one of his
paintings at Downton.
He's desperate to see it.
I assume it's just an excuse so
Charles can pay court to Mary.
He doesn't want to come. He wrote to
introduce his friend Simon Bricker.
~ I can invite Charles if you'd like.
~ I don't mind either way.
I will ask him. We don't know Mr
Bricker. It might be easier if
Charles was here.
~ Don't forget I'm away from Tuesday.
~ I wish I knew where you were going.
I haven't a clue. I expect we'll
drive around for a few days
and stop and sketch when we see a
view we like.
~ Who's this with?
~ Annabelle Portsmouth. It'll be fun.
How was your morning, Papa? Have you
decided where to put the memorial?
~ No.
~ Carson?
Not yet, my lady.
It's difficult to please everyone.
Bella Davis telephoned to talk about
her work with Russian refugees in
York.
~ Are there many Russian refugees in
York? ~ I'm afraid so.
They're scattered all over Europe.
Trying to establish communities to
save their culture after the ravages
of revolution.
Ghastly for them, eh, Tom?
I feel sorry for anyone exiled from
their own country.
I pity those who stayed behind
only to be tortured and murdered in
their thousands.
Leave him alone, Papa.
I was at the hospital today
and Mrs Henderson has done the most
generous thing
and given a wireless to the ward so
that they can listen to music and
the news
and sometimes even a play. I can't
tell you how it brightens things up.
I'm told that they're far more
efficient now
~ and much easier to tune.
~ No.
~ But...I haven't asked anything.
Shall we go through and let the
servants get in here?
Hello.
Dawn raid?
Look who it is. Come on, my lady.
Hello, Mrs Drewe.
I hope I'm not being a nuisance.
Hello, darling.
Hello. How are you?
Why don't you sit there, my lady?
Have they started cleaning up after
the fire?
They're doing it now. Thank heaven it
was only my room.
God, I was stupid.
It's wonderful the interest you take
in her, my lady.
Perhaps you'll keep an eye on her as
she grows.
I'm sure I will.
It would be a blessing if you would.
After all, she's almost a foundling.
No parents of her own.
~ No family, no-one to turn to.
~ What are you saying?
We're her family now?
I know. But there's a limit to what
we can do with three of our own.
I don't understand you. Marigold is
one of our own.
~ Or very nearly. ~ All I'm saying is
her ladyship could prove to be a
real blessing
if she'd only take an interest.
She seems a bright little thing to
me.
~ Well, I'd have to think about it.
~ Course you will.
Because if people get used to seeing
you together, you can't just duck
out.
That's why we must think carefully
and only take it on if I'm sure.
You could be a sort of godmother.
That's it.
~ Yes, I could be Marigold's godmother.
~ She's got a godmother.
We had her christened and my
sister's -
Talk it over with his lordship,
why don't you?
~ See what he thinks. ~ Maybe I could
take her up to the house to visit my
niece and nephew.
My eye. How lucky would she be?
It is all very good of you, my lady,
I'm sure.
Give it a thought. Then we'll see.
~ Sorry. ~ Dr Clarkson has just been
telling me about the latest report
of the drug insulin.
~ Oh. ~ It's going to make a great
difference to many lives.
~ I'm quite sure of that.
~ I agree.
We're a backwater here but, heaven
knows, we've our share of diabetes.
A diagnosis will no longer be a
death sentence.
I'm glad to see your old interests
are reasserting themselves.
~ Why do you say that? ~ Mrs Crawley's
been distracted lately.
With Lord Merton frisking around her
skirts and getting in the way.
You make too much of it.
Do I? We've been invited to tea with
Lord Merton at Cavenham.
I opened the letter this morning.
Maybe you're the real quarry and
he's only hunting me to throw you
off the scent.
I may be older than I was but I can
still tell when a man is interested.
I believe Cavenham Park has some
beautiful gardens.
Though it's the wrong time of year
to see them.
The promise of the gardens in summer
will be the final worm on the hook.
Honestly, I'm as good at being
teased as the next man
but even my sense of humour has its
limits.
Off you go, Miss Goody Two Shoes.
You can play the holy mother all you
like, you still nearly got me
sacked.
Leave her alone.
Oh, gallant Mr Molesley. She's never
told you though, has she?
Miss Baxter has had troubles in the
past
which you tried to use against her.
Until her ladyship put a stop to it.
~ That is all I need to know.
~ I knew she hadn't told you.
Barrow. Could you please tell Mrs
Patmore I'm here?
Very good, my lady.
Mrs Patmore, Lady Rose.
A delicious dinner, Mrs Patmore.
Thank you very much.
You wanted a word?
Only if it's convenient, my lady.
But, you know that young woman who
works at the school?
~ Miss Bunting. Mr Branson's friend.
~ Yes. I didn't like to ask him in
case he found it awkward.
I was wondering if she might be
prepared to take on some extra work.
But suppose they telephone Lady
Portsmouth.
She's promised she'll cover for me.
I feel quite nervous. And I'm not
even going.
We'll choose the clothes carefully
so you can take them on and off
without my help.
Well, I'll have his help.
Honestly, my lady. You'd better hope
I never write my memoirs.
There is one thing I've got to ask
you.
~ I'm really sorry, but I must.
~ Go on.
I have to sure there aren't
any...consequences.
What sort of consequences?
Well, you know.
No, I don't.
Oh, my God. Er...
I mean, I beg your pardon, my lady.
But you see I can't just go into a
shop and buy something.
What if I were recognised?
But I wouldn't know what to buy.
I've thought of that.
I have a copy of Marie Stopes's
book.
It tells you everything.
Well, won't he take care of it?
I don't think one should rely on a
man in that department, do you?
~ But suppose I'm recognised?
~ But you won't be?
And even if you are, you're married.
With a living husband.
Why shouldn't you buy one?
Is it true that Lady Rose wants his
lordship to buy a wireless?
Whether he will or not's another
matter.
I like the idea of a wireless.
To hear people singing and talking in
London and all sorts.
What's so good about that when you
can go to a music hall in York?
I'd rather hear a live singer.
If you're looking for Miss Baxter,
she's still upstairs.
Why do you have to make everything
sound so nasty?
I'm nasty about Miss Baxter because
she came here to help me and she's
broken her word.
I doubt that's how she'd put it.
Do you think with her past she'd
come near a house like this?
She'd be lucky to get work in a
public laundry.
~ I'm sure she's grateful. ~ Then she's
a funny way of showing it.
You do know she's a thief.
Stole her mistresses jewels.
There must be more to it than that.
No. She sneaked up to the bedroom,
snatched up the pieces,
pearl necklaces, diamond bracelets,
put them in her pockets.
Then tried to make it look as if
someone had broken in.
~ She was obviously unsuccessful.
~ They gave her five years but she
only served three.
Came out a few months before I
brought her up here so don't say she
doesn't owe me.
~ Has Mrs Bates come down yet?
~ Not yet.
We were just discussing your friend.
Miss Baxter.
Is she my friend particularly?
She seems to think so.
I know you mean to lead me into
further inquiry but I couldn't care
less what you think, Thomas.
~ On that subject or any other.
~ I agree.
No, you don't.
Cos you listened to the story,
didn't you?
What was that about?
Oh, nothing.
I must remember to organise a car to
meet Charles Blake and his friend.
~ They'll be here at teatime. ~ Are we a
hotel that never presents a bill?
You've already made that joke.
~ There you are. I need your advice.
~ How flattering. What is it?
~ Should I go?
~ No. No, it's not a secret.
I've been talking to Mr Drewe. Did
you know they've taken in a child?
~ The daughter of a friend who died.
~ How kind of them.
The girl is very endearing and I
think I'd like to be involved in her
future. To help her in some way.
Maybe with school fees or something.
I've money from my articles and
Grandpapa's trust.
Has Drewe put you up to this?
No. But I'd like to take an active
interest.
It'd be good for me.
It's your money. Do what you like
with it.
But you can't just give the child up
when you get bored.
I won't get bored.
Cousin Robert, did you see this
article about how wirelesses are
getting cheaper and more reliable?
~ No. ~ I just thought it was
interesting.
No.
What's Mr Branson's pal doing down
here?
Why? Don't you approve?
Last time she came, she gave them
all an earful.
I cannot solve the mystery. How are
you getting on with the memorial?
His Lordship is resisting the idea
of the garden.
~ You don't agree with him?
~ Well, as it happens, I do.
~ What? ~ I don't believe in your garden
of remembrance.
In a town, maybe.
But the Yorkshire scenery is our
garden of remembrance.
I'd prefer to see a memorial at the
heart of village life so we'd pass
it on the way to church or the shop
~ and give a thought to the boys who
fell. ~ You surprise me, Mrs Hughes.
I was disappointed in his Lordship,
but I'm more disappointed in you.
Every relationship has its ups and
downs.
Yes, miss.
Erm...
Is there a lady I could deal with?
Very good, madam. If you'll just
wait there.
I've not quite made up my mind.
Why not serve the gentleman first?
That's kind of you. Packet of safety
razor blades, please.
~ That's sixpence, sir.
~ Thank you.
If we keep this up we'll have another
customer along soon.
Yes. Erm...
I would like to buy...
..one of these.
I can see you're married.
~ I am married, yes. ~ But you don't
with for any more children.
That's it. That's right.
There is always abstinence.
Of course there is but...
I don't want to take any risks
because of my health.
Oh, I see. Well, that does put a
slightly different colour on it.
Three and eleven.
~ Keep the change.
~ What about the instructions?
~ They can be very difficult to manage.
~ I'm sure it's perfect. Thank you.
I'll take half a crown a lesson.
That's five shillings a week.
You can use my sitting room if you
need somewhere private.
See you after school. Goodbye.
Wait a minute! That is Daisy's
busiest time.
~ I can't come any earlier. ~ Oh, well,
then. Perhaps - ~ I'm excited.
But I'll pay. It's not right that you
should waste your money on me.
~ No, I want to pay.
~ That's a nice thing you're doing.
Is it? Well, I think I've been a
damn fool and doubled me workload!
I wondered who was in here.
We're just sorting out some things
for Rose's refugees.
Poor Rose.
Why are you so against getting a
wireless?
I wish she'd just say it. "Cousin
Robert, please buy a wireless for
Downton."
~ I wouldn't mind.
~ That's because you're American.
I find the whole idea a kind of
thief of life.
People waste hours huddled around a
box listening to someone burbling
inanities from somewhere else.
But surely now with the latest news
and it must be a boon for the old.
What do you think, Bates?
I can't see the Dowager with a
wireless, my lady.
It's a fad. It won't last.
Oh, no. Not that one.
This is nice.
Lord Grantham said it was the
coldest house in Yorkshire.
Ah, you're here. I'm so pleased.
~ How charming it is.
~ Oh, we do our best.
I know it's the wrong time of year
but I would love to see the gardens.
Shouldn't we allow Lord Merton to
tell us how he's planned our visit?
~ Of course.
~ It is his house.
Yes. I know that.
You've been very quiet all day.
~ Have I?
~ I wish you'd tell me what it is.
Very well.
Last night Mr Barrow chose to give
me an account of your history.
He was bound to, sooner or later.
His version is a bleak one, which
will not surprise you.
~ What did he say? ~ Well, for a start,
he seemed to suggest
that you were in some sort
of...privileged position.
I was a trusted senior ladies maid
to a good woman
in a rich and respectable household.
But then he said that...you just
took your employer's jewels.
Snatched them up and put them into
your pocket.
I stole a pearl necklace with a ruby
clasp.
Two diamond bracelets and four
rings.
Did he tell you I tried to pretend
it was a burglary?
Well, then. I think you have all the
relevant information.
There must be something more.
There must have been a cause, a
reason for you to do such a thing.
~ What sort of cause? ~ I don't know.
Someone that you cared for
needed money for an emergency and
you were desperate to help.
I was a common thief, Mr Molesley.
A convicted criminal. A jailbird.
~ I don't believe you.
~ Because you don't want to.
I would only say that I am not that
person now.
When you've finished your tea, we
can walk the terraces, if you like.
That sounds ideal.
I recently read a book on the
science of quarantine
and I've been looking forward to
discussing it with you.
We mustn't bore Lady Grantham.
Oh, you're right. You see, I need
your guiding hand to keep me in
check.
Mrs Crawley is never happier than
when she has a chance to use her
guiding hand.
Are you, dear?
~ How pretty this room is.
~ Thank you.
Mama re-did all these rooms in the
'80s. She had good taste, I think.
Is one allowed to brag about one's
mother?
So the late Lady Merton didn't
change it?
Ada didn't use it much.
She thought it was draughty being so
near the front door.
I suppose she had a point.
If you don't like being quite so
near the front door.
Well, I think it's enchanting.
It's a woman's room, though.
Of course.
The library and the dining room are
masculine
the drawing rooms and the music rooms
are feminine. Or so I was taught.
I meant that it needs a woman's
presence to make sense of it.
When I'm on my own in here I feel
like a bull in a china shop.
~ Why aren't you going with her?
~ What?
With Lady Mary? She'll be away for
almost a week.
Yes but they're driving round. They
don't know where they'll stay or
anything.
~ She and Lady Portsmouth? ~ Yes.
~ It doesn't sound like Lady Mary.
It sounds a bit bohemian.
I suppose she's allowed to get away
from it all if she wants to.
~ Like anyone.
~ Yes. I suppose she is.
What do you make of Edith's burst of
generosity with the Drewe girl?
In all probability her beloved
Gregson is dead and she has to sit
and watch her sisters' children play.
She wants someone to love. It's as
simple as that.
The problem will come when she has a
child of her own to distract her.
Let's cross that bridge when we come
to it.
And let's hope the Drewes don't get
sick of her in the meantime.
~ Was it ghastly?
~ I didn't know where to look.
But when I thought about it
afterwards it seemed unfair to
punish me like that.
Suppose I had eight children and
didn't want any more? Wouldn't I
have the right?
~ I agree completely. ~ I feel like
going back and ordering a baker's
dozen.
One's enough for now.
~ Mr Bricker.
~ This is wonderfully kind of you.
You can see the painting now or
after dinner or wait until tomorrow.
It's entirely up to you.
I think I'd like a glimpse of it
later this evening.
I can take a proper look in the
daylight with my wits about me.
You look as if you've spent the
winter away from these shores.
~ I've been in Alexandria.
~ Really? I don't envy you.
~ I'm not very good at abroad.
~ she's in the kitchen?
I don't know what room she's in. She
was giving a lesson to Daisy and
she's still here.
Shouldn't we invite her to dinner?
As she's your friend.
I don't think Lord Grantham would
like it. Not after last time.
But it seems terribly grand and
unfriendly not to. I'll ask Cora.
How are you? I haven't seen you for
ages.
Have I neglected you? I'm sorry.
No need to apologise. Although I
think you might perhaps have told me
I was not the lucky winner.
~ Why would you say that?
~ Because it's perfectly obvious.
Well, I don't seem to have broken
your heart.
You sound disappointed.
Who is this fellow, anyway.
Simon Bricker? Just a chap I know.
He was talking about his book in
Boodle's.
~ I mentioned the painting here and
that was it. ~ He's very brown.
Lucky chap.
Charles, I'm sorry if I've hurt you.
It's just only lately that I've
started to come out of the mist.
And the mist is clearing around the
lithe and supple figure of Tony
Gillingham.
~ Maybe. ~ Well... Good luck to you both.
I mean it.
That's why I came here. So I could
wish you luck in person.
~ We should give her the option.
~ If you're certain.
~ I don't want to feel I'm imposing.
~ Don't be silly. This is your home.
~ Where's Tom going?
~ Miss Bunting is downstairs.
~ What? ~ She's been teaching one of the
maids in the kitchen.
~ Tom's gone to ask if she'd like some
dinner. ~ You're not serious.
She's the first friend Tom's made
that has nothing to do with us and
we must respect that.
So every time we entertain we must
invite this tinpot Rosa Luxemburg.
Who's she?
A German communist who was shot and
thrown in the canal.
We wouldn't wish that on Miss
Bunting.
I didn't see the time. I've left
Mrs Patmore cooking for everyone.
Tell her from me, you'll prove a
talented mathematician.
Whose idea was it to ask me? Yours?
No, it was Rose. Although it's a new
sensation for me not to be alone in
my opinions at the table.
If I've encouraged you to stand your
ground, I'm glad.
But I don't feel like putting either
myself or Lord Grantham through
another test of strength.
Please thank them and say good night
for me.
I don't need a car. I'm perfectly
happy to walk.
When in Rome.
But do you ever think you might have
been in Rome too long?
~ Why do you say that? ~ You needn't
always do what the Romans do.
~ There's more in you than that.
~ I wonder.
You could do anything you want if
you put your mind to it.
I can't deny it. It's good to hear
you talk as if I had a real future.
You do have a future. But not here.
Not with these people.
Your link to them is Cybil but from
the way you talk I think she was
unique in this family.
~ Free of prejudice, free from narrow
thinking. ~ That's true enough.
~ She was unique. ~ I just want you to
remember that you are the man
who tempted her over the park wall
to run away to freedom.
I was that man.
But I'm not sure I can be that man
again.
You can be. I know it.
Good night.
Where's your friend?
She couldn't stay. She had to get
home.
What a relief.
What were you doing in Alexandria?
Escaping the winter and looking at
beautiful things.
Beautiful and very ancient things.
~ I don't agree. ~ So you're
collecting clothes for
the Russian refugees.
I said no at first because, well, it
didn't feel terribly me.
But then I thought about them
leading their lives before the fall.
~ Doing everything you would do.
~ Exactly.
Dancing and shopping and seeing
their friends and then suddenly
being thrown out to fend for
themselves in the jungle.
Well, I thought I had to help if I
could.
It's lucky Miss Bunting refused our
invitation or she'd give tell us
how they're aristocrats and they
deserve it.
She believes the old regime was
unjust.
She hopes the new system will be an
improvement. Does that make her a
firebrand? Because I agree with her.
And you don't think certain acts
of savagery forfeit sympathy
for the perpetrators?
It was terrible, of course. But the
English killed King Charles the
first
to create a balance between the
throne and parliament.
~ I didn't kill him personally. ~ I
didn't shoot the Imperial Family.
Goodness. Is this what they call a
lively exchange of views?
It's about now that Papa usually
fetches his gun.
Mary, don't tease Mr Bricker.
He's come to see a painting
and finds himself in the middle of a
civil war.
I don't think we'll split tonight.
~ They'll only fight if we do.
~ You want to see the picture and
delay is torment.
You read my mind.
Carson, how are we to move forward
with the memorial?
I suppose your position has not
changed.
I can see that I'm losing. I would
rather be convinced than defeated,
my lord.
And I am not yet convinced.
Cousin Robert?
Did you see that the King is going
to speak on the wireless?
~ It was in the paper today.
~ Don't be silly.
No, it's true. For the opening of
the British Empire Exhibition.
It's being broadcast on the 23rd.
I just thought you'd like to know.
~ Is this true, Carson?
~ I believe so, my lord.
Talking about the Empire too.
I wonder.
If the King wants to use the wireless
to speak to his people maybe we have
to listen.
I wouldn't say that, my lord.
Is it not a case of the King being
forced into accepting a humiliating
assignment by his ministers?
~ Are you saying the King is a weak
man, Carson? ~ Never that, my lord.
But even kings must bow to pressure
sometimes.
And should we not support him in his
hour of endurance?
Oh, cheer up. We can always hire one.
Surely we won't be corrupted if it's
only in the house for a day.
They said you were out here.
I thought I'd get some air before we
have our dinner.
I've let you down, haven't I?
No, I wouldn't say so.
You are who you are.
You made choices and you paid the
price for them.
Still, I'm not who you thought me.
It is not for me to pass sentence.
You've had enough of that.
I've changed.
I'm different now. I wish you could
believe me.
But you won't tell me why you did it
because I am not persuaded you could
have acted on your own.
Maybe not. But I don't want to talk
about that.
Because, alone or not, in the end,
I made the choice to steal.
And there's no point trying to pass
the sin along.
Then you won't allow me an opinion.
You see, you wouldn't have done it.
No matter who asked you to.
No matter what the provocation.
I don't claim that. If a man must
watch his loved ones starve,
who's to say what he'll do?
But I wasn't starving, was I?
Believe me.
I'd give a limb to rewrite that
whole chapter of my life.
But I can't, Mr Molesley.
Even for you.
I can't.
Do you have a clear record of how it
came to be here?
The second Earl was our collector.
He bought it when he was quite a
young man on his grand tour.
~ Which was when? ~ 1789. We've a letter
from his mother.
She's heard about the fall of the
Bastille and her son was going
through France.
She sent it by special messenger.
~ Mothers. ~ Some things never change.
Lots of things never change.
Tomorrow I can show you some other
pictures he brought back if you have
time.
I have all the time in the world.
I should enjoy it very much.
~ There's coffee in the drawing room.
~ Thank you.
We'll be right in.
Isis, come here, girl.
I can't believe it. When she
explained how it all worked,
~ I could see it at once. ~ Well, this
is our lady of the numbers.
If I'd had a teacher like her,
things might have turned out
different.
They've not turned out so badly,
have they?
I'm glad to see some smiles at the
end of a long day.
Daisy's singing the praises of Miss
Bunting and her teaching.
I should keep it to yourself. She's
not a favourite with Mr Carson.
~ Why, what's she done? ~ It's not what
she's done it's what he calls her
dangerous ideas.
Dangerous or not I'm sure they're
good ideas.
Careful, he'll think you've been
infected.
~ What's this? ~ Daisy's worried she's
been infected with a cold from the
delivery boy.
Oh, his lordship and I are walking
down to the village tomorrow to look
at possible sites.
Erm, I don't like it when we're not
on the same side.
We're different people, Mr Carson.
We can't always agree.
I know.
But I don't like it.
I can't make a decision, Baxter,
until you tell me the whole truth.
I have, my lady.
I don't mean you tried to shield
yourself, quite the contrary.
To be honest, I don't know why I
haven't dismissed you out of hand.
I employ a jewel thief to look after
my jewels. It doesn't make sense!
~ I don't know what to say. ~ I should
sack you for just concealing it.
Should I take this as my dismissal?
I don't know. I don't know why not
but I don't know.
What was the matter with Tom?
Papa will blame his friend Miss
Bunting for filling his ears with
poison but I'm not sure.
~ He has so little life away from us.
~ He's had no life since Cybil died.
But I've a feeling he's turning back
into who he really is.
~ Is that a bad thing?
~ For us, maybe. But not for him.
Well, I'm going up.
Good night, you two.
Do you think there's a chance
cousin Robert might get a wireless?
Well, if he won't get one for the
King, your cause is hopeless.
That's true.
I loved Rose's definition of
ordinary life.
Dancing and shopping and seeing one's
friends.
I'm going to bed too.
I'm worn out.
But I hope you'll be happy for me.
If it is Tony in the end.
Nothing will make me happier than
seeing you happy.
But please be absolutely sure before
you decide.
~ Why do you say that?
~ Because you're cleverer than he is.
That might have worked in the last
century
when ladies had to hide their brains
behind good manners and breeding.
~ But not now. ~ I don't agree. I think
Tony is quite as clever as I am.
Then one of us is right...
and one is wrong.
I'm not some overheated housemaid
drooling over a photograph of
Douglas Fairbanks.
Plantagenets are as susceptible as
housemaids when it comes to sex.
Are we talking about sex or love?
That is a question mankind has
wrestled with since the dawn of time.
Good night.
Poor Tom. He's nothing more than a
ventriloquist dummy
for that terrible woman's ideas to
come spewing out of his mouth.
Maybe she's given him confidence to
say what he really thinks.
Not to sit in silence listening to a
thousands things he disagrees with.
She'll steal him away from us. She's
pulling him back to the other side.
I hope not. But if he feels he has
to go, that's what he must do.
~ Well, he's not taking Sybbie.
~ Don't be silly.
I mean it. I am not having Cybil's
only child
snatched from everyone she loves
to be brought up by some harpie in
an American sewer!
If the time comes, then we will talk
to Tom.
And I suggest we try to be a little
more calm about it.
For heaven's sake! Can't I be angry
when our eldest grandchild
is about to be stolen from us for
ever?
And tell your friend Bricker to stop
flirting with Isis.
There is nothing more ill-bred than
trying to steal the affections of
someone's else's dog!
Very well. I'll tell him.
To stop flirting.
I think I've put everything in.
~ Your packet's here, my lady.
~ Thank you.
I don't think there's anything too
difficult to fasten.
Lord Gillingham can always help.
Are you certain you know what you're
doing?
I believe so.
Anna, the way things are going,
life will be lived in much closer
quarters in future.
My grandparents lived in vast rooms
surrounded by staff.
If they disagreed, they'd hardly have
known it.
But it won't be like that for us.
I must be sure I'm right to want this
man.
As my friend...
..as my lover...
as my husband.
Well, I think it's a big risk.
Please. I can't be lectured twice in
one evening.
I've already had a ticking off from
Mr Blake.
~ You didn't tell him. ~ Only that I
thought Lord Gillingham was the one.
The point is I want to marry again.
And I absolutely don't want to
divorce.
Well, I wish you luck, my lady.
~ Morning.
There you are. I'm afraid it's the
perfect position for me.
Millions of men killed, my lord,
and we'll remember them
with a stone cross for women to stop
by and gossip?
I prefer to say that as people go
about their business, we remind them
of the men who died.
They gave their lives for our
freedom and we'll remember them with
a convenient step to sit for a
moment and tie up your shoelace.
~ Afternoon, my lord. ~ Hello,
Mrs Elkith. What are you up to?
I'm just waiting for our Robbie.
He likes to say hello to his father
sometimes after school.
It's good of you to make a special
journey.
Oh, no. He comes with me when I'm on
the way to the shop
or the post office and takes a
chance to visit the grave then.
My Bob was a lovely man and a
wonderful dad and I don't want our
Robbie to forget him.
Not if I can help it.
No. No, of course you don't.
Thank you, Mrs Elkith. Your words
have made quite an impression on me.
Don't you agree, Carson?
I do, yes. Quite an impression.
My lord.
Why is it called a wireless when
there's so many wires?
I don't know.
Nothing's happening.
It's just warming up, my lady.
Is that Jack Hylton?!
Oh, golly, isn't this thrilling?!
What's this I see?
Servants loitering in the hall with
her ladyship due at any moment.
Look at that. If I touch it,
will I get a shock?
You'll only get a shock if you
listen to it.
I think it's exciting.
We're catching up, Mr Carson.
Whether you like it or not, Downton
is catching up with the times we
lived in.
That is exactly what I am afraid of.
Hello.
Before I go, I hope we're all united
in the plan.
~ It's very kind of you, my lady.
Isn't it, Margie? ~ Very kind.
I just want every opportunity for
little Marigold.
~ It's very generous. ~ And you won't
mind me being part of her life?
~ She needs a chance to dream. ~ You
mustn't fill her head with too many
dreams, my lady.
This is a wonderful opportunity
you're offering. Thank you.
I'll see you soon.
~ Bye-bye.
~ Bye.
~ What's the matter?
~ Why should anything be the matter?
You could have been more gracious.
I don't want this place to be her
doll's house.
And Marigold her doll. To be kissed
and petted
and cast aside when she loses
interest.
~ She won't lose interest.
~ How can you be sure? ~ I am sure.
I'll be in the yard. Tell me when
the food's ready.
Hands, please.
"It gives me the greatest pleasure
and satisfaction
to come here today with the Queen
for the purpose of opening the
British Empire Exhibition."
~ I suppose he can't hear us.
~ No, it doesn't work like that.
..the board of management."
Miss Mary Crawley.
Welcome to Liverpool, Miss Crawley.
I hope you enjoy your stay.
I'm sure I will.
Well, you have heard the voice of
His Majesty King George V.
What do you think, Carson? Mrs
Hughes, the King on the wireless?
I prefer to think of him on his
throne, my lord.
To me it's a good thing. To make him
less of a myth, more of a man.
Well, I hope you've all taken
something of value from it.
Mrs Hughes is right. The radio
somehow makes the King more real.
The monarchy has thrived on magic
and mystery.
Strip them away and people may think
the royal family is just like us.
Well, would that be so wrong?
Well, only if they want to stay at
Buckingham Palace.
It was as though he was right in the
room with us.
Cheer up, Mr Barrow.
Weren't you pleased to hear the King?
I expect it's difficult for you with
Jimmy gone.
We all need a special friend from
time to time.
I wasn't special to him. Not truly.
I don't agree. I think he liked you.
Maybe. A little.
But I don't think I'm very likeable
to people here.
Do you want to be?
There are times when I'd like to
belong?
Does that sound funny?
Not to me. Not at all.
Shall I have it collected in the
morning, my lord?
~ Must he? ~ Do we need to get rid of it
in quite such a hurry now it's here.
~ Put it in the small library.
~ Thank you for changing your mind.
I wasn't aware I'd decided against
it.
You can clear this for now.
It's such a pity Mary had to miss it
for a boring sketching trip.
It's mad not to give a false name.
Always make a lie as truthful as
possible.
If you're seen, you have the right
name, you're alone in your room.
And why shouldn't you be in
Liverpool?
How did you manage to get the rooms
connected?
Well, I'm not a complete halfwit.
Nor, happily, is the manager.
So, what's the plan?
It's a simple one. We'll go down to
Church Street for a delicious
dinner.
After which, we'll come back.
And...make love?
Exactly.
We'll make love all night.
And, in fact, for as long as either
of us has any stamina left.
And who can say fairer than that?
I meant to ask how you got on this
morning.
Oh, we've settled it.
It's going to be in the village.
Well, I hope you're not too upset.
I only asked to be convinced.
My walk through the village
convinced me.
~ And...there's a bonus.
~ What's that?
It puts us back in agreement,
Mrs Hughes.
I'm not comfortable when you and I
are not in agreement.
You're very flattering.
With talk like that you make me want
to check to see that my hair's tidy.
~ Get away with you.
~ No, I mean it.
~ There's a policeman to see you,
Mr Carson. ~ A policeman?
It's just Sergeant Willis,
Mr Carson.
Hello, Mr Willis.
Thank you, Mr Barrow. You're
scaremongering has not succeeded.
That'll be all. Sit down, Mr Willis.
Have a cup of tea.
~ How can I help you?
~ Well, it's an odd business but we
may as well get down to it.
A man stayed here last year, Mr Alex
Green. Worked for Lord Gillingham.
I remember him well. Why wouldn't I
when he died so very tragically not
long after?
Well, that's all I need. I've just
been told to check that you remember
him. Thank you.
And to give warning that we might
need to ask some questions.
I don't understand.
Well, something's turned up.
And before they take it further,
they're trying to establish its
significance.
But what is that? What's turned up?
A witness.
~ What would it be like to go somewhere
no-one knows us? ~ Why do you say that?
If a man seduced me, I would not let
any grass grow under his feet.
~ I want you to tell me the missing
element of your story? ~ If I don't?
She can't have our child and that's
flat!
Allow me to present Prince Kuragin.
Goodness! Granny has a past.